aldifoods.com 2019-12-31

# Online Privacy Notice | ALDI US

## Information We Collect

We may obtain certain personal information through our Sites.  The types of personal information we may collect include:

·        Your name, nickname, postal address, email address and telephone number;

·        gift card number and security code;

·        your geolocation data if you use our ALDI USA mobile application to search for a store;

·        contact information of others to whom you ask us to send information;

·        in connection with our careers pages, personal information contained in your resume, cover letter or other documents submitted online, including your name and education history; and

·        content and other data posted to our Sites, blog and social media pages, and information we obtain through ALDI-related social media apps, tools, widgets and plug-ins. 

[Back to Top  
](https://www.aldi.us/en/online-privacy-notice/#c408703)

## Information we Collect By Automated Means

When you use our Sites, we may collect certain information by automated means, using technologies such as cookies, web server logs, image pixels, web beacons and JavaScript.

Cookies are files that websites send to your computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify your browser or to store information or settings on your device.  Our Sites may use cookies (such as HTTP and HTML5 cookies) and Flash cookies, as well as other types of local storage (such as browser-based or plugin-based local storage).[ **   **](https://www.aldi.us/en/online-privacy-notice/)Your browser may tell you how to be notified when you receive certain types of cookies and how to restrict or disable certain cookies.  You also may be able to delete your Flash cookies or adjust your Flash cookie settings by visiting the Adobe Flash [Website Storage Settings Panel](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html) and [Global Storage Settings Panel](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager03.html).  Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to use all of the features of our Sites or other websites and online services.

In conjunction with gathering information through cookies, our web servers may log information such as your device type, operating system type, browser type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone where your device is located.  The web server logs also may record information such as the address of the web page that referred you to our Site and the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet.  They also may log information about your interaction with this Site, such as which pages you visit.  To control which web servers collect information by automated means, we may place tags on our web pages called “Web beacons,” which are small files that link web pages to particular web servers and their cookies.  We also may send instructions to your device using JavaScript or other computer languages to gather the sorts of information described above and other details about your interactions with the Sites and to provide you with content related to your online activities.  Both we and others (such as our service providers or advertising networks) may collect personal information about our visitors’ online activities over time and across third-party websites. Our Sites are not designed to respond to “do not track” signals received from browsers.

We may use third-party web analytics services on our Sites, such as those of Matomo.  The information collected for this purpose (including your IP address, time of request, address of the web page that referred you to one of our Sites, browser characteristics, operating system characteristics and other information collected by automated means) may be disclosed to or collected directly by these service providers.  You may choose not to have a unique web analytics cookie identification number assigned to your computer to avoid the aggregation and analysis of data collected on this website.  To prevent the collection of data on this website, please check the option below:

In addition, when you use our ALDI USA mobile application, we may collect certain information by automated means, including the application name, device type, version of the application and version of the operating system.

## How We Use The Information We Obtain

We may use the information we obtain through the Sites to:

·        Offer and provide products, services and information to you;

·        communicate about, and administer your participation in, special events, programs, surveys, contests, sweepstakes, and other offers or promotions;

·        send information to others;

·        respond to and communicate with you about your requests, questions and comments;

·        process claims we receive in connection with our products and services;

·        enable you to post to our blog and interact with ALDI through social media;

·        operate, evaluate and improve our Sites and business (including developing new products and services; managing our communications; determining the effectiveness of our sales, marketing and advertising; and analyzing and enhancing our products, services and Sites, including our mobile applications);

·        perform data analyses and other processing (including market and consumer research, trend analysis, financial analysis, anonymization, encryption and tokenization of personal information);

·        process employment applications, including by assessing qualifications, verifying information, conducting reference or other employment-related checks (if you submit an application for employment);

·        protect against, identify and prevent fraud or other criminal activity, claims and other liabilities; and

·        comply with and enforce applicable legal requirements, relevant industry standards and our policies, including our [Terms of Use](https://www.aldi.us/en/terms-of-use/).

We may use the information collected through automated means to provide a more tailored shopping experience and for market research, data analytics and system administration purposes, such as to determine whether you’ve visited us before or are new to the Sites, and for compliance with our legal obligations, policies and procedures.  We also may use this information to target custom content and ads to you on the Sites and other websites, including as described in the Interest-Based Advertising section below. 

The providers of third-party plug-ins on our Sites, such as social sharing tools, may use automated means to collect information regarding your use of the Sites and your interactions with the plug-ins.  This information is subject to the privacy policies or notices of the plug-in providers and is not subject to this U.S. Online Privacy Notice.  We are not responsible for these providers’ information practices.

## Internet-Based Advertising

Data about your activities online is being collected on our Sites for use in providing advertising tailored to your individual interests.  You may choose whether or not to have your information collected for that purpose.  This section of the U.S. Online Privacy Notice provides details and explains how to exercise that choice.

You may see certain ads on other websites because we participate in advertising networks administered by third parties and utilize third party service providers.  Networks track your online activities over time by collecting information through automated means, including through the use of the technologies described in the “Information We Collect By Automated Means” section above, and they use this information to show you advertisements that are tailored to your individual interests.  The information they collect includes information about your visits to our Sites, such as the pages you have viewed.  This collection and ad targeting takes place both on our Sites and on third-party websites that participate in the ad networks, such as sites that feature advertisements delivered by the ad networks.  This process also helps us track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts.  To learn more about ad networks, including how to opt out, visit [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices).  We may also use third party service providers, such as Google’s Double Click to collect information through automated means for the purpose of direct Aldi-related advertising and other content to you. 

## Information We Share

We do not sell or otherwise share personal information about you, except as described in this U.S. Online Privacy Notice.  We share personal information with third parties who perform services on our behalf.  We also may share the personal information we obtain with our affiliates.

Our Weekly Ads pages are operated by Fusion92 (“Fusion92”), whose own privacy policies apply to the collection, use and disclosure of information obtained through the Weekly Ads pages by Fusion92 and its partners (such as Fusion92 ad networks).  Fusion92 may use browser cookies, HTML 5 web storage, pixels and web beacons on our Weekly Ads pages.  Similarly, the collection, use and disclosure of information by social media sites in connection with ALDI’s social media pages and accounts, including on Facebook, Pinterest, Instagram, Twitter and YouTube, is subject to those sites’ privacy policies. 

We also may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law, regulation or legal process (such as a court order or subpoena), (ii) in response to requests by government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities, or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity.  We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including in the event of a reorganization, dissolution or liquidation). 

## Your Options

We offer you certain choices about how we communicate with you and what information we collect from you.  To update your preferences, ask us to remove your information from our mailing lists or submit a request, please contact us as specified in the How To Contact Us section of this U.S. Online Privacy Notice.

## Notice To California Residents

Subject to certain limits under California law, California residents may ask us to provide them with (i) a list of certain categories of personal information that we have disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, and (ii) the identity of those third parties.  To make this request, California residents may contact us as specified in the [How to Contact Us](https://www.aldi.us/en/online-privacy-notice/#c408693) section below. 

## International Users

As noted, this is a U.S. focused web site.  The Sites are not directed to users outside of the United State and are administered from the United States.  Information provided through the Site may be uploaded to a cloud and/or transferred to the U.S.    By providing information to the Sites you consent to the transfer, processing and/or use of the information to the U.S. and/or through a cloud.   In the event you utilize this site from outside of the U.S., you consent to the uploading of any information to a cloud and the transfer of the information to the U.S.

## Links To Other Websites

Our Sites may contain links to other websites for your convenience and information.  These websites may be operated by companies not affiliated with ALDI, such as our Weekly Ads pages.  Linked websites may have their own privacy policies or notices, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites.  We are not responsible for the content of any websites that are not affiliated with ALDI, any use of those websites, or the privacy practices of those websites.

## How We Protect Personal Information

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information you provide against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use.  Nevertheless, please keep in mind that "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet.

## Children's Privacy

Our Sites are not directed to children under the age of thirteen and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen on our Sites.  If you become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a visitor under the age of thirteen on our Sites, please contact us with a request to delete the information from our records.

## Updates To Our U.S. Online Privacy Notice

This U.S. Online Privacy Notice may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal information practices. 

## How To Contact Us--Access, Correct or Delete Information

If you have any questions about this U.S. Online Privacy Notice, or if you would like us to access, update, correct or delete information we have about you or your preferences, please use the Contact Us form available on the Sites or write to us at:

ALDI Inc.  
Attention:  Customer Service  
1200 N. Kirk Rd.   
Batavia, IL 60510 

We reserve the right to request information to authenticate your request.   We may take a reasonable period of time to respond to any request to update or modify any information, limit use of information or to opt out of or unsubscribe from any communications.   If you request the deletion,  modification or limitation of use of your personal information maintained by us we will promptly review your request and respond.   If we grant your request, such information may be retained for a period of time in our backup systems as a precaution against system failures. Some information may be retained for longer periods as required by law, contract or auditing requirements. In some circumstances we will not be able to limit use of your personal information without unsubscribing you from communications or deleting your information.
